<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ana Cozma's Tech Blog</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Ana Cozma's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 19:34:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform vs Helm for Managing K8s Objects</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-vs-helm-for-managing-k8s-objects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 19:34:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-vs-helm-for-managing-k8s-objects/</guid><description>When I started migrating to Kubernetes (K8s) I discovered that I can use Terraform for managing not only the infrastructure, but also I could define the K8s objects in it, but I also could use Helm to handle that. But what would be a good way to handle this?
In this post we will cover Terraform and Helm for managing Kubernetes clusters with some code snippets and an idea on how you can use them together to get you started.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Alternative to the Template provider on Apple M1 MBP</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-alternative-to-deprecated-template-prov/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 17:52:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-alternative-to-deprecated-template-prov/</guid><description>We ran into an issue while applying our Terraform infrastructure on a M1 Mac where we were making use of the Terraform Provider Template.
When applying it, we were getting the following error:
template v2.2.0 does not have a package available for your current platform, darwin_arm64 Since the provider is archived, we need to find an alternative.
What does archiving mean? Per Terraform Archiving Providers documentation.
The code repository and all commit, issue, and PR history will still be available.</description></item><item><title>K8s - Fix Helm release failing with an upgrade still in progress</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/k8s-fix-helm-release-failing-with-an-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 17:49:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/k8s-fix-helm-release-failing-with-an-upgrade/</guid><description>This article applies to: Helm v3.8.0
Helm helps you manage Kubernetes applications — Helm Charts help you define, install, and upgrade even the most complex Kubernetes application. More details on Helm and the commands can be found in the official documentation.
Assuming you use Helm to handle your releases, you might end up in a case where the release will be stuck in a pending state and all subsequent releases will keep failing.</description></item><item><title>Terraform - Handling the deletion of a non-empty AWS S3 Bucket</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-deletion-of-non-empty-s3-bucket/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:39:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/terraform-deletion-of-non-empty-s3-bucket/</guid><description>This article applies to Terraform v1.1.4
When using Terraform to manage your infrastructure you will end up in the situation when you want to remove some resources.
You can do this in several ways, but most of the time you can also just remove the Terraform configuration by commenting it out the code, or removing the calling of the module, run terraform apply and it will get rid of the resources.</description></item><item><title>K8s - How to restart Kubernetes Pods</title><link>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/k8s-how-to-restart-pods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:35:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ana-cozma.github.io/blog/posts/k8s-how-to-restart-pods/</guid><description>This article applies for Kubernetes v1.15 and above.
Kubernetes, also known as K8s, is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
It groups containers that make up an application into logical units for easy management and discovery. But what if something happens to the container? In this case, you might need a quick and easy way to restart it.
Kubernetes Pods usually run until there is a new deployment that will replace them.</description></item></channel></rss>